http://www.providenceproject.org/privacy-policy

Latest government Coronavirus update
Alcohol Rehab
Alcohol RehabThe Providence Projects offer a range of alcohol rehabilitation programmes ranging from 4 weeks through to 12 weeks.Read More
Drug Rehab
Drug RehabIf you or a loved one are experiencing problems with drugs, The Providence Projects can help. Our drug rehab centre, is widely regarded as the finest affordable private drug rehab programme in the UK.Read More
Cannabis Rehab
Cocaine Rehab
Crack Cocaine Rehab
Heroin Rehab
Ketamine Rehab
Prescription Drug Rehab
Programme Details
Drug Rehab Cost
Drug Rehab: Facts, Stats & Myths
Gambling Rehab
Gambling RehabThe Providence Projects are one of only a few organisations in the UK providing comprehensive gambling rehab programmes.Read More
Programme Details
Gambling Rehab Cost
Do I have a Gambling Problem?
Gambling: The Facts
Detox
DetoxDetox is the first step on your path to recovery. We offer a range of alcohol and drug detox programmes which are supervised 24/7 by our highly experienced and friendly medical and therapeutic teams.Read More
Prices
Cost of RehabHere at the Providence Projects, our aim is to provide the best-quality and most affordable addiction treatment in the UK. Find out more about the cost of our private rehab programmes here.Read More
Cost of Rehab
Admission
Make a ReferralOur dedicated and compassionate admissions team are on-hand 24/7 to guide you through the admissions process. Find out more about how to book in to our drug, alcohol and gambling rehab programmes.Read More
Are you looking to admit yourself?
Are you looking to admit a loved one or a friend?
About Us
About UsThe Providence Projects has offered drug, alcohol and gambling rehab programmes since our doors opened in 1996. Find out more about us and how we can help you start your recovery journey today.Read More
Programme Details
Why Providence?
Our Location
Our Facilities
Meet The Team
Paul Spanjar
Media Coverage
London Rehab
London Rehab & Addiction ServicesThe Providence Projects offers a range of drug, alcohol and gambling rehabilitation programmes in both London and Bournemouth.Read More
London Rehab Services
Other Services
Other ServicesThe Providence Projects offers a full range of additional and personalised services for both the individual and their families. Find out more about our individualised rehab services here.Read More
Sober Management
Recovery Coaching
Sober Transport
Drugs and Alcohol in the Workplace Solutions
Intervention
Menu
Get help now
Close
Alcohol Rehab
Alcohol RehabThe Providence Projects offer a range of alcohol rehabilitation programmes ranging from 4 weeks through to 12 weeks.Read More
Programme Details
Alcohol Rehab Cost
Alcohol Detox
Alcohol: The Facts
Drug Rehab
Drug RehabIf you or a loved one are experiencing problems with drugs, The Providence Projects can help. Our drug rehab centre, is widely regarded as the finest affordable private drug rehab programme in the UK.Read More
Cannabis Rehab
Cocaine Rehab
Crack Cocaine Rehab
Heroin Rehab
Ketamine Rehab
Prescription Drug Rehab
Programme Details
Drug Rehab Cost
Drug Rehab: Facts, Stats & Myths
Gambling Rehab
Gambling RehabThe Providence Projects are one of only a few organisations in the UK providing comprehensive gambling rehab programmes.Read More
Programme Details
Gambling Rehab Cost
Do I have a Gambling Problem?
Gambling: The Facts
Detox
DetoxDetox is the first step on your path to recovery. We offer a range of alcohol and drug detox programmes which are supervised 24/7 by our highly experienced and friendly medical and therapeutic teams.Read More
Prices
Cost of RehabHere at the Providence Projects, our aim is to provide the best-quality and most affordable addiction treatment in the UK. Find out more about the cost of our private rehab programmes here.Read More
Cost of Rehab
Admission
Make a ReferralOur dedicated and compassionate admissions team are on-hand 24/7 to guide you through the admissions process. Find out more about how to book in to our drug, alcohol and gambling rehab programmes.Read More
Are you looking to admit yourself?
Are you looking to admit a loved one or a friend?
About Us
About UsThe Providence Projects has offered drug, alcohol and gambling rehab programmes since our doors opened in 1996. Find out more about us and how we can help you start your recovery journey today.Read More
Programme Details
Why Providence?
Our Location
Our Facilities
Meet The Team
Paul Spanjar
Media Coverage
London Rehab
London Rehab & Addiction ServicesThe Providence Projects offers a range of drug, alcohol and gambling rehabilitation programmes in both London and Bournemouth.Read More
London Rehab Services
Other Services
Other ServicesThe Providence Projects offers a full range of additional and personalised services for both the individual and their families. Find out more about our individualised rehab services here.Read More
Sober Management
Recovery Coaching
Sober Transport
Drugs and Alcohol in the Workplace Solutions
Intervention
Contact Us
Blog
NHS
Resource Hub
Media Coverage
Rehab Reviews
Home > Privacy Policy Privacy Policy
Get help now
Navigate
This is the privacy notice of THE PROVIDENCE PROJECTS REHAB GROUP LTD. In this document, “we”, “our”, or “us” refer to [trading or business or organisation or company name].
We are company number 08547370 registered in England.
Our registered office is at 17 Carysfort Road, Bournemouth, Dorset BH1 4EJ
Introduction
This is a notice to inform you of our policy about all information that we record about you. It sets out the conditions under which we may process any information that we collect from you, or that you provide to us. It covers information that could identify you (“personal information”) and information that could not. In the context of the law and this notice, “process” means collect, store, transfer, use or otherwise act on information.
We regret that if there are one or more points below with which you are not happy, your only recourse is to leave our website immediately.
We take seriously the protection of your privacy and confidentiality. We understand that all visitors to our website are entitled to know that their personal data will not be used for any purpose unintended by them, and will not accidentally fall into the hands of a third party.
We undertake to preserve the confidentiality of all information you provide to us, and hope that you reciprocate.
Our policy complies with UK law accordingly implemented, including that required by the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
The law requires us to tell you about your rights and our obligations to you in regards to the processing and control of your personal data. We do this now, by requesting that you read the information provided at www.knowyourprivacyrights.org
Except as set out below, we do not share, or sell, or disclose to a third party, any information collected through our website.
The bases on which we process information about you
The law requires us to determine under which of six defined bases we process different categories of your personal information, and to notify you of the basis for each category.
If a basis on which we process your personal information is no longer relevant then we shall immediately stop processing your data.
If the basis changes then if required by law we shall notify you of the change and of any new basis under which we have determined that we can continue to process your information.
1. Information we process because we have a contractual obligation with you
When you create an account on our website, buy a product or service from us, or otherwise agree to our terms and conditions, a contract is formed between you and us.
In order to carry out our obligations under that contract we must process the information you give us. Some of this information may be personal information.
We may use it in order to:
verify your identity for security purposes
sell products to you
provide you with our services
provide you with suggestions and advice on products, services and how to obtain the most from using our website
We process this information on the basis there is a contract between us, or that you have requested we use the information before we enter into a legal contract.
Additionally, we may aggregate this information in a general way and use it to provide class information, for example to monitor our performance with respect to a particular service we provide. If we use it for this purpose, you as an individual will not be personally identifiable.
We shall continue to process this information until the contract between us ends or is terminated by either party under the terms of the contract.
2. Information we process with your consent
Through certain actions when otherwise there is no contractual relationship between us, such as when you browse our website or ask us to provide you more information about our business, including job opportunities and our products and services, you provide your consent to us to process information that may be personal information.
Wherever possible, we aim to obtain your explicit consent to process this information, for example, by asking you to agree to our use of cookies.
Sometimes you might give your consent implicitly, such as when you send us a message by e-mail to which you would reasonably expect us to reply.
Except where you have consented to our use of your information for a specific purpose, we do not use your information in any way that would identify you personally. We may aggregate it in a general way and use it to provide class information, for example to monitor the performance of a particular page on our website.
If you have given us explicit permission to do so, we may from time to time pass your name and contact information to selected associates whom we consider may provide services or products you would find useful.
We continue to process your information on this basis until you withdraw your consent or it can be reasonably assumed that your consent no longer exists.
You may withdraw your consent at any time by instructing us https://providenceproject.org/contact-us. However, if you do so, you may not be able to use our website or our services further.
3. Information we process for the purposes of legitimate interests
We may process information on the basis there is a legitimate interest, either to you or to us, of doing so.
Where we process your information on this basis, we do after having given careful consideration to:
whether the same objective could be achieved through other means
whether processing (or not processing) might cause you harm
whether you would expect us to process your data, and whether you would, in the round, consider it reasonable to do so
For example, we may process your data on this basis for the purposes of:
record-keeping for the proper and necessary administration of our business
responding to unsolicited communication from you to which we believe you would expect a response
protecting and asserting the legal rights of any party
insuring against or obtaining professional advice that is required to manage business risk
protecting your interests where we believe we have a duty to do so
4. Information we process because we have a legal obligation
We are subject to the law like everyone else. Sometimes, we must process your information in order to comply with a statutory obligation.
For example, we may be required to give information to legal authorities if they so request or if they have the proper authorisation such as a search warrant or court order
This may include your personal information.
5. Complaints regarding content on our website
We attempt to moderate user generated content, but we are not always able to do so as soon as that content is published.
If you complain about any of the content on our website, we shall investigate your complaint.
If we feel it is justified or if we believe the law requires us to do so, we shall remove the content while we investigate.
Free speech is a fundamental right, so we have to make a judgment as to whose right will be obstructed: yours, or that of the person who posted the content that offends you.
If we think your complaint is vexatious or without any basis, we shall not correspond with you about it.
6. Job application and employment
If you send us information in connection with a job application, we may keep it for up to three years in case we decide to contact you at a later date.
If we employ you, we collect information about you and your work from time to time throughout the period of your employment. This information will be used only for purposes directly relevant to your employment. After your employment has ended, we will keep your file for six years before destroying or deleting it.
7. Sending a message to our support team
When you contact us, whether by telephone, through our website or by e-mail, we collect the data you have given to us in order to reply with the information you need.
We record your request and our reply in order to increase the efficiency of our business.
We keep personally identifiable information associated with your message, such as your name and email address so as to be able to track our communications with you to provide a high quality service.
8. Complaining
When we receive a complaint, we record all the information you have given to us.
We use that information to resolve your complaint.
If your complaint reasonably requires us to contact some other person, we may decide to give to that other person some of the information contained in your complaint. We do this as infrequently as possible, but it is a matter for our sole discretion as to whether we do give information, and if we do, what that information is.
We may also compile statistics showing information obtained from this source to assess the level of service we provide, but not in a way that could identify you or any other person.
Use of information we collect through automated systems when you visit our website
Cookies
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer’s hard drive by your web browser when you visit any website. They allow information gathered on one web page to be stored until it is needed for use on another, allowing a website to provide you with a personalised experience and the website owner with statistics about how you use the website so that it can be improved.
Some cookies may last for a defined period of time, such as one day or until you close your browser. Others last indefinitely.
Your web browser should allow you to delete any you choose. It also should allow you to prevent or limit their use.
Our website uses cookies. They are placed by software that operates on our servers, and by software operated by third parties whose services we use.
When you first visit our website, we ask you whether you wish us to use cookies. If you choose not to accept them, we shall not use them for your visit except to record that you have not consented to their use for any other purpose.
If you choose not to use cookies or you prevent their use through your browser settings, you will not be able to use all the functionality of our website.
We use cookies in the following ways:
to track how you use our website
to record whether you have seen specific messages we display on our website
to keep you signed in our site
to record your answers to surveys and questionnaires on our site while you complete them
to record the conversation thread during a live chat with our support team
Personal identifiers from your browsing activity
Requests by your web browser to our servers for web pages and other content on our website are recorded.
We record information such as your geographical location, your Internet service provider and your IP address. We also record information about the software you are using to browse our website, such as the type of computer or device and the screen resolution.
We use this information in aggregate to assess the popularity of the webpages on our website and how we perform in providing content to you.
If combined with other information we know about you from previous visits, the data possibly could be used to identify you personally, even if you are not signed in to our website.
Information we obtain from third parties
Although we do not disclose your personal information to any third party (except as set out in this notice), we sometimes receive data that is indirectly made up from your personal information from third parties whose services we use.
No such information is personally identifiable to you.
Data may be processed outside the European Union
Our websites are hosted in England.
We may also use outsourced services in countries outside the European Union from time to time in other aspects of our business.
Accordingly data obtained within the UK or any other country could be processed outside the European Union.
Access to your own information
To obtain a copy of any information that is not provided on our website you may send us a request at info@providenceproject.org.
After receiving the request, we will tell you when we expect to provide you with the information, and whether we require any fee for providing it to you.
Removal of your information
If you wish us to remove personally identifiable information from our website, you may contact us at info@providenceproject.org.
This may limit the service we can provide to you.
Verification of your information
When we receive any request to access, edit or delete personal identifiable information we shall first take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or otherwise taking any action. This is important to safeguard your information.
Use of site by children
We do not sell products or provide services for purchase by children, nor do we market to children.
If you are under 18, you may use our website only with consent from a parent or guardian
Encryption of data sent between us
We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificates to verify our identity to your browser and to encrypt any data you give us.
Whenever information is transferred between us, you can check that it is done so using SSL by looking for a closed padlock symbol or other trust mark in your browser’s URL bar or toolbar.
Retention period for personal data
Except as otherwise mentioned in this privacy notice, we keep your personal information only for as long as required by us:
to provide you with the services you have requested;
to comply with other law, including for the period demanded by our tax authorities;
to support a claim or defence in court.
Compliance with the law
Our privacy policy has been compiled so as to comply with the law of every country or legal jurisdiction in which we aim to do business. If you think it fails to satisfy the law of your jurisdiction, we should like to hear from you.
However, ultimately it is your choice as to whether you wish to use our website.
Review of this privacy policy
We may update this privacy notice from time to time as necessary. The terms that apply to you are those posted here on our website on the day you use our website. We advise you to print a copy for your records.
If you have any question regarding our privacy policy, please contact us.
Call us now
0800 955 0945
Rehab prices starting from
£895
per week
See Prices
Live chat
Chat confidentially online with one of our addiction specialists.
Chat now
Speak to us
Our addiction specialists are here 24 hours a day on 0800 955 0945.
Call us
Get immediate confidential help now
Request a call back -
NameEmail Address*
Telephone*Your Message Protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.*
I consent to my data being used inline with the Privacy Policy
CAPTCHA
Get help now
Get started on your journey to recovery
Get help now
Close
×
Get Help Now
Get started on your journey to recovery.
Request a call back
Send us your details and one of our expert advisors will call you back.
Call me
Live chat
Chat confidentially online with one of our addiction specialists.
Chat now
Call 0800 955 0945
Our addiction specialists are here 24 hours a day on 0800 955 0945.
Call us now
Get immediate confidential help now
NameEmail Address*
Telephone*Your Message Protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.
I consent to my data being used inline with the Privacy Policy
CAPTCHA
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue we assume that you consent to receive all cookies on our website. Read more
×
